Finding Aid for Media Resources Center (University of Michigan) films and videotapes, 1930s and 1948-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Series AF - Archives Film
  - Graduation, June, 1963. C.P. Snow, Speaker 1963, 851831-AF-107-a-b
    - Graduation, June, 1963. C.P. Snow, Speaker 1963, 851831-AF-107-d; Miscellaneous footage of pre and post ceremony and some shots of honorary degree, (ground camera?)Features: C.P. Snow, Rev. John Burgess, Alden Dow, Nathan Eddy, John Gordon, Roman Jacobson, Emory Morris, Judge Tavares
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos/wp, col/b/w
  - UM Alumni Camp, Boyne City, August, 1963 1963, 851831-AF-108; General coverage of activity at the Alumni Camp, shots of water front, picnic. Bill Stegeth, camp director, describing Camp, square dancing, Dean Robertson lecturing. (Sound on col. pos. is not good.)Features: Bill Stegeth, UM-Camp Michigania; James Robertson, UM-LSA
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; wp, col; col, sil; sil; sot, 700
  - Technirama, Spring, 1963 1963, 851831-AF-109; Footage of varied activities at science and technology fair at North Campus and Main Campus, crowds of UM students and children viewing scientific exhibits.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; neg, col, sil, 600
  - Graduation, Fall, 1963, Willard Wirtz, Speaker 1963, 851831-AF-110; U.S. Secretary of Labor, W. Willard Wirtz, is commencement speaker. Footage of Sec. Wirtz and Pres. Hatcher conversing in Regents' Room prior to commencement. Footage of press conference held by Sec. Wirtz on same day. Features: W. Willard Wirtz, U.S. Secretary of Labor; Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; wp, col, sil, 100
  - President Harlan Hatcher 1963, 851831-AF-111; President Hatcher discusses many current UM problems, including the undergraduate program. Filmed on 12/13/63. Questions are read by Hazen Schumacher. Features: Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.; Hazen Schumacher, UM-TVC
    - Original:, 16mm film, wp, col, sof; sot, 400
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, sof, 396, 00:11:09
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF111.flv
  - Subendra Kumar Dey, October, 1963, 851831-AF-112; Mr. Dey is given an Honorary Degree in special ceremonies. Footage of Mr. Dey during casual sightseeing, at Union and on State St., Mr. Dey is shown with Pres. Hatcher in front of the Rackham Bldg. just before ceremony. Features: Subendra Kumar Dey; Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; wp, col, sil, 85
  - Lynn Townsend Receiving Business Leadership Award 1963, 851831-AF-113; Two UM Bus. Ad. students present Mr. Lynn A. Townsend, Pres. of Chrysler Corp. with the 1963 Business Leadership Award from the UM Graduate School of Business Administration. Features: Lynn Townsend
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; neg, b/w; b/w, sof; sof, 30; 30
  - Tuskegee Institute Choir, 851831-AF-114; Various shots of Tuskegee Institute Choir. Features: Tuskegee Institute Choir
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; wp; wp, col; col, sil, 100
  - Michigan State-Michigan Football 1963, 851831-AF-115; UM and MSU in tie game played to a capacity crowd in Ann Arbor. Extensive coverage of many plays. WP has best of the best action. Crowd shots. Footage of bands pre-game and half-time shows. (3 reels of game, 1 of band, 3 reels mag. track.)Features: Marching Band
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; pos; wp, col; col; col, sil; sil; sil; sot, 300; 300
  - Michigan State-Michigan Football 1963, 851831-AF-115-a; Coverage of UM Marching Band performance, pre-game shots, Hawaiian War Chant marching formation. (Total of four reels plus cutaways.)Features: Marching Band
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; wp; wp, col; col; b/w, sof; sof
  - Michigan State-Michigan Football 1963, 851831-AF-115-b; Coverage of pre-game band performance and crowd shots. Features: George Romney, Lenore Romney, UM Marching Band
    - Original:, 16mm film, wp; wp, col, sof, 300
  - Sorority Rush, 851831-AF-116; Footage of greeting of sorority guests, various shots of guests in sorority house. (Some of this footage has also been spliced into Archives #122.)Features: UM Sorority
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; pos; wp, col; col; col, sil; sil; sil,; 280; 280
  - Students on Campus, Registration Weekend, 1963 1963, 851831-AF-117; Miscellaneous shots around Main Campus during Registration Week, Fall, 1963.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, b/w, sil, 300
  - Navy-Michigan Football Game, Fall, 1963 and WVGR 1963, 851831-AF-118; Stadium and Campus shots. (Some snow scenes spliced in.) UM Marching Band, UM Stadium, football crowd, cheerleaders, UM Grand Rapids radio station WVGR, Middleville Village Sign. Features: Marching Band
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sil, 480
  - Navy-Michigan Football Game, Fall, 1963 and WVGR 1963, 851831-AF-118-a; Miscellaneous shots as follows: Navy/UM Football - mostly crowd shots, WVGR UM Radio in Grand Rapids, Engr. Dick Clarke at controls, Tom Montgomery at racks, WVGR sign on building and the station tower. Features: Dick Clarke, Engr. WVGR; Tom Montgomery, Engr. WVGR
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; pos; pos; wp, col; col; col; b/w, sil; sil; sil; sil
  - Stewart Udall, U.S. Secretary of the Interior, 851831-AF-119; Footage of Secretary Udall at the UM television studio, being made up for his appearance on the UM television series "Understanding Our World". (see series B "Secretary of the Interior: Stewart Udall")Features: Stewart Udall, U.S. Secretary of the Interior
    - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w; b/w, sil; sil, 100; 100
  - University Alumni, 1963 1963, 851831-AF-120; Professor is shown instructing students on basic atomic structure - protons, electrons.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, b/w, sil, 103
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 103, 00:02:52
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF120.flv
  - Mideast Basketball Championships 1964, 851831-AF-121; Filmed are the Mideast Basketball Championships held in Milwaukee. U-M basketball team winning against Loyola, Ohio University also plays at the Championships. (Film #121 on reel with #122, also on reel with #s114, 121,122,125-128.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; pos; pos; wp, col; b/w; b/w, sil; sil; sil, 200; 200; 200
  - Snowstorm in Ann Arbor: Campus in Seasons 1964, 851831-AF-122; Various shots around Main Campus of students struggling (happily) through heavy snows. Old Observatory Building is shown. (Some footage of Archives #116 spliced in on one reel.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; pos; wp, col; col; col, sil; sil; sil
  - Gymnastics Training, Winter 1964 1964, 851831-AF-123; Gymnastics practice. Newt Locken (Coach) with team practicing various gymnastics events. Features: Newt Locken, UM-Ath.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; wp, col; b/w, sil; sil, 210; 200
  - Gymnastics and Hockey 1964, 851831-AF-124; Footage of a UM gymnastics meet and of a UM hockey game at Yost arena.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sil, 121
  - Hockey Practice 1964, 851831-AF-125; Footage of UM hockey team practicing in Yost Arena.
    - Original:, 16mm film, wp, col, sil, 92
  - Wrestling Match 1964, 851831-AF-126; Brief footage of a UM wrestler in a wrestling match.
    - Original:, 16mm film, wp, col, sil, 99
  - Swimming Practice, Winter 1964 1964, 851831-AF-127; Swimming practice. Includes shots of Coach Stager. Features: Gus Stager, UM-Ath.
    - Original:, 16mm film, wp, col, sil, 75
  - Swimming Meet 1964, 851831-AF-128; Footage of a swimming meet between Michigan and Indiana.
    - Original:, 16mm film, wp, col, sil, 94
  - Basketball Practice 1964, 851831-AF-129; Footage of basketball team warming-up at practice. (Footage is dark.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, wp, col, sil, 75
  - Illinois-Michigan Basketball Game 1964, 851831-AF-130; Footage from Michigan basketball victory over Illinois.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; wp, col; b/w, sil; sil, 200
  - NCAA Basketball Semi-finals, Duke-Michigan 1964, 851831-AF-131; Brief footage of Michigan's loss to Duke in the NCAA semi-final basketball game held in Kansas City, one shot of team coming out of dressing room.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; wp, col, sil, 200
  - 1963 Business Leadership Award Winner 1964, 851831-AF-132; Donald C. Cook is presented 1963 Business Leadership Award, April, 1964. Mr. Cook is president of American Electric Power Co. and former chairman of the Securities and Exchange Commission. Features: Donald C. Cook, Pres. American Electric Power Co.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; pos, b/w; col, sil; sof; sot; at, 100; 100; 100
  - Tuskegee Institute Founder's Day, Spring 1964 1964, 851831-AF-133; President Hatcher and other dignitaries make several speeches at ceremonies marking Founders Day at Tuskegee Institute. Footage of Tuskegee campus, nursing students, ROTC, and a campus parade. (On core with Archives #135-137.)Features: Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sil, 200
  - Richard Wilson Lecturing to Engineering Class 1964, 851831-AF-134; Dr. Wilson, 1964 Faculty Award Winner, is filmed lecturing to engineering class at Flint Extension. (On core with Archives 135-137.)Features: Richard Wilson, UM-Eng.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sil, 200
  - Spring Rain in Ann Arbor, 851831-AF-135; Spring rainstorm on Campus. Various shots of students with umbrellas, jumping over puddles, etc. (On core with Archives #134-137.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; wp, col, sil, 100
  - Michigras Parade and Dance Contest, Spring 1964, 851831-AF-136; Michigras parade and frug dance contest, Pres. and Mrs. Hatcher and Sonny Elliott are in parade, also parade shots of floats, bands, crowd, and the dance contest on the mall. Features: Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.; Mrs. Harlan Hatcher; Sonny Elliott, TV Weathercaster, Bunny (from Detroit Playboy Club?)
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sil; at, 200
  - Richard Wilson Lecturing to Engineering Class 1964, 851831-AF-137; Richard Wilson, Faculty Award Winner, lectures to his engineering class on campus in Ann Arbor. (On core with Archives 134-137.)Features: Richard Wilson, UM-Eng.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sil, 100
  - D. Dumond & J. Griffin Discussing Civil Rights 1964, 851831-AF-138; Faculty Award Winner, Dwight Dumond talks about the FBI civil rights investigation. John Griffin, author of "Black Like Me," talks about civil rights. (Some imperfection in film but footage is usable.) Features: Dwight Dumond, UM-Hist.; John Griffin, author
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sof; sot, 400
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, sof, 400, 00:11:19
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF138.flv
  - David Dennison Interview 1964, 851831-AF-139; David Dennison, Chairman of Physics Department and 1964 Faculty Award Winner, discusses his career at UM, problems and solutions in running the Physics Department. (Needs repair.)Features: David Dennison, UM-Physics
    - Original:, 16mm film, wp, col, sof; sot, 600; 90; 600
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, sound, 611, 00:17:01
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF139.flv
  - Kennedy Peace Corps Plaque at Union Dedication 1964, 851831-AF-140; President Hatcher and dignitaries are shown on platform in front of Michigan Union. Film consists mostly of crowd shots, a solemn crowd gathered in front of the Union. (Also includes misc. shots of old School of Music and students on the Diag.)Features: Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.; Harlan Cleveland.
    - Original:, sot
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sil, 862, 00:24:01
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF140.flv
  - Music School (Old) 1964, 851831-AF-141; Exterior shot of door and wall of building with bike rack near the door. Students shown arriving on bikes, parking, and entering door. Also students shown on the Diag in Spring.
    - Original:, 16mm film, wp, col, sil, 100
  - Music School Move to North Campus, May, 1964 1964, 851831-AF-142; Shots of moving vans at Lane Hall, Burton Tower, and Maynard St. School of Music Building.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, silent, 00:02:53
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
  - Music School, Organ 1964, 851831-AF-143; Footage of Music School's move, one of the organs in the Maynard St. School of Music is dismantled prior to being moved to the new building on North Campus.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, silent, 00:01:37
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF143.flv
  - Sigma Kappa Sorority Initiation, May, 1964, 851831-AF-144; Sorority members filmed in their living room exchanging gifts. Pan-Hellenic president Ann Wickens is present. Features: Ann Wickens, Pan-Hellenic Pres.; Sigma Kappa Sorority
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; wp, col, sil, 100
  - Michigan Band at World's Fair & Rockefeller Centre 1964, 851831-AF-145; Michigan Concert band plays at GM Display and at American Pavilion. Shots of Prof. Revelli, Gov. Romney, Gov. Rockefeller. Next day concert at Rockefeller Centre is also filmed. (Total of six reels)Features: William D. Revelli; UM-Music; George Romney; Nelson Rockefeller
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; pos; wp, col; col, sil; sil, 400; 400
  - Commencement, 1964. Pres. Lyndon Johnson, Speaker 1964, 851831-AF-146; A work print copy of film with sound of a portion of President Johnson's "Great Society" speech.
    - Original:, 16mm film, wp; wp, col; col, sil; sil; sot, 100
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, sil, 100, 00:02:49
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
  - Commencement, 1964. Pres. Lyndon Johnson, Speaker 1964
    Original camera footage (6 reels) and separate magnetic sound track (2 reels) recorded from WUOM radio feed of the ceremony and speech. The audio captures the entire ceremony and Johnson’s speech. The film, shot with two cameras, does nor record the entire ceremony or speech. None of the original film reels have been synched with the audio. Film shows all honorary degree recipients;. extensive cutaways before, during, and after the graduation ceremonies, many crowd shots; Pres. Johnson shown landing and departing by Marine helicopter, entering and leaving the stadium. Features: Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.; G. Mennen Williams, George Romney, Merle Curti, John C. Bugher, Clarence L. Johnson, Pres. Lyndon B. Johnson
    - Commencement, 1964. Pres. Lyndon Johnson, Speaker 1964, 851831-AF-146-A; Portions of Johnson's Speech Features: Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.; G. Mennen Williams, George Romney, Merle Curti, John C. Bugher, Clarence L. Johnson, Pres. Lyndon B. Johnson
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, silent, 297, 00:08:15
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-AF146.flv
    - Commencement, 1964. Pres. Lyndon Johnson, Speaker 1964, 851831-AF-146-B; 1964 Commencement, Pres. Lyndon Johnson speaker. [Stage Camera] Features: Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.; G. Mennen Williams, George Romney, Merle Curti, John C. Bugher, Clarence L. Johnson, Pres. Lyndon B. Johnson
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, silent, 714, 00:19:50
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-AF146.flv
    - Commencement, 1964. Pres. Lyndon Johnson, Speaker 1964, 851831-AF-146-C; 1964 Commencement, Pres. Lyndon Johnson speaker. [Platform camera,]
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, silent, 742, 0:20:36
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-AF146.flv
    - Commencement, 1964. Pres. Lyndon Johnson, Speaker 1964, 851831-AF-146-D; 1964 Commencement, Pres. Lyndon Johnson speaker. ["Alley's Work Print"} Features: Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.; G. Mennen Williams, George Romney, Merle Curti, John C. Bugher, Clarence L. Johnson, Pres. Lyndon B. Johnson
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, silent, 606, 00:16:50
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-AF146.flv
    - Commencement, 1964. Pres. Lyndon Johnson, Speaker 1964, 851831-AF-146-E; 1964 Commencement, Pres. Lyndon Johnson speaker. [AB 3000 original color]
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, silent, 636, 00:17:28
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-AF146.flv
    - Commencement, 1964. Pres. Lyndon Johnson, Speaker 1964, 851831-AF-146-F; 1964 Commencement, Pres. Lyndon Johnson speaker. [AB 4000 original color]
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, silent, 459, 12:38
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-AF146.flv
    - Commencement, 1964. Pres. Lyndon Johnson, Speaker 1964, 851831-AF-146-G; mag track 1
      - Original:, 16mm film, mag track, sound, 505, 00:14:09
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-AF146.flv
    - Commencement, 1964. Pres. Lyndon Johnson, Speaker 1964, 851831-AF-146-H; mag track 2
      - Original:, 16mm film, mag track, 778, 00:21:22
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-AF146.flv
    - Commencement, 1964. Pres. Lyndon Johnson, Speaker 1964, 851831-AF-146-I; mag track 3
      - Original:, 16mm film, mag track, sound, 1472, 00:39:44
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-AF146.flv
    - Commencement, 1964. Pres. Lyndon Johnson, Speaker 1964, 851831-AF-146-J; mag track 4
      - Original:, 16mm film, mag track, 00:8:25
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-AF146.flv
  - Cazzie Russell, Basketball Star, May 1964, 851831-AF-147; Sophomore Basketball star Russell talks (in front of the Physics and Astronomy Bldg.) about his experiences as an athlete and as a Negro. (Several takes, some without sound.) Features: Cazzie Russell, UM Basketball Star
    - Original:, 16mm film, wp, col, sof; sot, 300
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, sof, 369, 00:07:30
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF147.flv
  - Ralph Sawyer, Retiring VP for Research, Interview 1964, 851831-AF-148; Vice Pres. Ralph A. Sawyer discusses UM research activities as they evolved and grew in scope during his years as VP for Research. VP Sawyer stands atop the VA Hosp. Excellent panoramic views of North Campus. Features: Ralph A. Sawyer, UM-VP
    - Original:, 16mm film, wp, col, sof; sot, 400
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, sof, 386, 00:10:45
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF148.flv
  - Fritz Crisler, Director of Athletics, Spring, 1964 1964, 851831-AF-149; Filmed in empty UM stadium. Mr. Crisler recollects many experiences and talks about a wide range of topics on the 25th anniversary of his association with UM. Features: Fritz Crisler, UM-Ath.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; wp, col, sof; sil, at, 200
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sof, 1175, 00:32:40
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 2)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF149.flv
  - Ralph A. Sawyer, Retiring VP for Research 1964, 851831-AF-150; Ralph A. Sawyer, former Dean of the Rackham School of Graduate Studies, discusses changes in the Graduate School over the years, and his long career at UM. Features: Ralph A. Sawyer, UM-VP
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sof; sot, 600
  - Tuskegee Institute Campus, Summer 1964 1964, 851831-AF-151; Shots of various buildings on Tuskegee campus, students, exterior shot of George Washington Carver Museum and bust of George Washington Carver.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sil, 99, 00:02:48
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 3)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF151.flv
  - Michigan Daily Editor, May, 1964 1964, 851831-AF-152; Editor of the Michigan Daily talks about his views of UM campus mostly about size problems and solutions. (Needs repair.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sof; sot, 300
  - Harlan Lane describing the SAID System 1964, 851831-AF-153; Psychology Prof. Harlan Lane, a Distinguished Faculty Award Winner, describes research project SAID, a computer system used to teach foreign languages. Extensive footage of the SAID system in operation. Features: Harlan Lane, UM-Psych.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; pos, col; col, sof; sof; sot, 1100; 1100
  - Buhl Laboratory Dedication, Spring, 1964 1964, 851831-AF-154; The new Genetics Lab on Catherine St. is dedicated, Spring, 1964. Many UM VIP's including VP Sawyer, Pres. Hatcher, Dr. Neel. Ceremony takes place outside on lawn. (On core with #155-157.)Features: Ralph A. Sawyer, UM-VP; Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.; James V. Neel, UM-Genetics
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, sil, 70, 00:01:58
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 3)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF154.flv
  - Phoenix Reactor, Summer 1964 1964, 851831-AF-155; Footage of fuel loading at Phoenix nuclear reactor on North Campus, old fuel being removed and being lifted into special truck, interior shots of fuel being handled with mechanical arms. (On core with 154-157) (Needs repair.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 299, 00:05:32
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 3)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF155.flv
  - Dr. Luther Foster, Pres., Tuskegee Institute 1964, 851831-AF-156; Dr. Foster discusses aspects of Tuskegee Institute - University of Michigan cooperative programs, Summer, 1964. (On core with 154-157.)Features: Luther Foster, Pres. Tuskegee Institute
    - Original:, 16mm film, wp, sof; sot; at, 300
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sof, 336, 00:09:21
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 3)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF156.flv
  - Norman Miller, Head of Women's Hospital, Interview 1964, 851831-AF-157; Norman Miller, head of the UM Women's Hospital and Faculty Award Winner, talks about his hobbies, views on change in the UM Medical School over the years. (On core with 154-157.)Features: Norman Miller, UM-Med.
    - Original:, 16mm film, sot; at
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, sof, 282, 00:07:53
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 3)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF157.flv
  - William Fry Teaching at University Hospital 1964, 851831-AF-158; William Fry, Distinguished Faculty Award Winner, Summer, 1964, teaching in a classroom at UM Hospital. Features: William Fry, UM-Med.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; pos, col; col, sil; sil, 100; 100
  - Campus views and anthropological dig, Grand Rapids 1964, 851831-AF-159; Various Campus shots: Law School, Pres. Kennedy Peace Corps Plaque, UM stadium, empty. General coverage of a dig by Anthropology Dept. of Hopewell Culture American Indian Mounds near Grand Rapids. (Footage used in TV program "Hopewell Heritage.")Features: James Griffin, UM-Anthro.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; pos; pos, col; col; col, sil; sil; sil, 200; 200; 200
  - Campus Shots - Angell Hall, Music School, Students circa 1964, 851831-AF-160; Various shots around campus. Excellent footage of Angell Hall. Shots of students studying on Diag and lawn. Poor quality footage of the Music School. (On core with #161.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; pos;, col; col, sil; sil, 200; 200
  - Music School, Summer 1964 1964, 851831-AF-161; Various shots of the interior of the new Music School Building including the library and Professor Brossart's piano studio and the band music sorting racks. Features: R. Eugene Brossart, UM-Music
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; wp, col; col, sil,sil, 300; 300
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sil,284, 00:07:55
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 3)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF161.flv
  - Students Looking at Peace Corps Plaque 1964, 851831-AF-162; UM students looking at plaque on Michigan Union commemorating President Kennedy's announcement of the Peace Corps. Good close-up of the plaque.
    - Original:, 16mm film,; wp, col, sil, 100; 100
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, col, sil,102, 00:02:53
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 3)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AF162.flv
  - UM Fresh Air Camp 1964, 851831-AF-163; Footage from the UM camp for delinquent boys includes shots of boys and counselors at various camp activities.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos; wp, col; col, sil; sil, 200; 200
  - Rocket Launch circa 1964, 851831-AF-164; Footage from the UM rocket launch site shows rocket launcher, data recording equipment, launch crew and VIP observers, loading of the rocket, and a rocket launch.